<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Questions resolved upon by both houses of Parliament with an order for the speedy rigging of the Navy, for the defence of the kingdom.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1642</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A38078</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E2213</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36409</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15689670</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 15689670</idno>
            <idno type="VID">104382</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A38078)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 104382)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1591:86)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Questions resolved upon by both houses of Parliament with an order for the speedy rigging of the Navy, for the defence of the kingdom.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 broadside.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Joseph Hunscott,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1641 [i.e. 1642]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>At head of title: March 2 [1642]</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: cropped at top, with some loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1642-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="resolutions">
            <pb facs="tcp:104382:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
            <head>Queſtions reſolved upon by both Houſes of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. VVith an Order for the ſpeedy Rigging of the Navy, for the defence of the Kingdom.</head>
            <p>
               <label>Reſolved upon the Queſtion by both Houſes of Parliament,</label>
               <lb/>
THat the Kingdom be forthwith put into a poſture of defence, by Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of both Houſes, in ſuch a way as is already agreed upon by both Houſes of Parliament.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Reſolved, &amp;c.</label>
               <lb/>
That the Lords be deſired to joyn with the Houſe of Commons in this Vote.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Reſolved, &amp;c.</label>
               <lb/>
That a Committee ſhall be appointed to prepare a Declaration upon theſe two Heads, <hi>viz.</hi>
               <list>
                  <item>1. To lay down the juſt cauſes of the fears and jealouſies given to theſe Houſes: and to cleer theſe Houſes from any jealouſies conceived againſt them.</item>
                  <item>2. And to conſider of all matters that may ariſe upon this Meſſage of His Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty, and to declare their opinions what is fit to be done thereupon.</item>
               </list>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="document">
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>Die Mercurii, 2 Martii. 1641.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>THe Lords and Commons in this preſent Parliament aſſembled, having re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived advertiſement of extraordinary preparations made by the neighbor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Princes, both by Land and Sea; the intentions whereof have been ſo re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſented, as to raiſe an apprehenſion in both Houſes, That the publike Honour, Peace, and Safety of His Majeſty and His Kingdom cannot be ſecured, unleſſe a time<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly courſe be taken for the putting of this Kingdom into a Condition of defence, at Sea, as well as Land. It is therefore Ordered, by the Lords and Commons afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> Lord high Admirall of England, do forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with give effectuall direction and order, that all and every the Ships belonging to His Majeſties Nauy, which are fit for ſervice, and not already abroad, nor deſigned for this Summers Fleet, be withall ſpeed Rigged, and put in ſuch a readineſſe, as that they may ſoon be fitted for the Sea; And that his Lordſhip do alſo make known un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to all the Maſters and Owners of ſuch Ships as now are in, or about any the Harbours of this Kingdom, and may be of uſe for the publike defence thereof, That it will be an acceptable ſervice to the King and Parliament, if they likewiſe will cauſe their Ships to be Rigged, and ſo far put in a readineſſe, as they may be at a ſhort warning ſet forth to Sea, upon any immergent occaſion, which will be a means of great ſecuri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty to his Majeſty and his Dominions.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Joſeph Hunſcott.</hi> 1641.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
